Hey there.
I really hope you're enjoying the first week
of the program.
I just wanted to give you a little preview
of what's coming up,
so you have a better idea of what you'll be
doing.
Next week, Louise will be showing you how
we can tell
if our networks are learning what we want
them to learn.
We do this through what's called validation.
We test the network on a subset of the data,
to see how well they're performing.
After that, Andrew Trask, author of grokking
Deep Learning
and a general deep learning expert,
will lead you through building the networks
that can predict if a movie review is positive
or negative.
Then, we'll be learning about convolutional
networks,
these networks are able to identify objects
and images.
You'll be using them in the second project,
where you'll be classifying images based on
objects
that are hidden in those images.
After that, we'll be covering recurrent neural
networks.
This is a network architecture that can learn
information
about how the data is sequenced.
For example, which word comes next in a sentence.
You can do awesome things with these,
like generate text with music,
and achieve state-of-the-art results in natural
language processing.
Finally, we'll get into unsupervised learning,
that is networks that learn only from the
data itself.
Specifically, you'll be learning about generative
adversarial networks,
also known as GANs.
GANs are the major advancement in deep learning,
allowing networks to understand data better
than anything
we've used before.
The inventor of GANs - Even Goodfellow - will
teach you
how to build and train these awesome Deep
Learning Network.
Thanks so much for enrolling in this program,
it's a pleasure for all of us to be teaching
you.
Deep learning is the future of artificial
intelligence,
and this is your first step in the new world.
See you in class.