We design our projects
to be challenging,
and you'll almost certainly
feel frustrated at times.
But what's unique about learning with
Udacity is that we provide you with
several kinds of human, personal support
options to make sure you succeed and
graduate.
To find out more about this,
I'm going to bring Lisbeth.
>> I'm Lisbeth Ortega,
Udacity's community manager.
To begin with,
every project you create is code
reviewed with detailed personal feedback
by a friendly expert and returned to
you, on average, within 24 hours.
You simply can't get personalized
feedback like this anywhere else.
And, additionally, you can submit these
projects as many times as you need.
Our reviewers are trained, vetted,
global experts who love to provide
critical feedback and help you grow.
Additionally, you have access to
a dedicated helpful mentor who
acts as a personal adviser
throughout the program.
Your mentor is always accessible, and
you can reach out to them when you need.
They'll help you stay on track and make
the most of your Udacity experience.
This is another service you'll
only find with us at Udacity.
If you have particular technical
questions, you can ask them on our
forums and receive answers from Udacity
staff so that you'll never stay stuck.
Finally, our student body is the most
important part of the Udacity
experience.
Our students form a worldwide community
of which you are now an integral member.
In this nanodegree program,
as in all Udacity programs, your peers
will be an invaluable resource to you.
And just as in a brick and
mortar institution,
it's important to get to know them.
To facilitate this, we work hard
to introduce you to your peers.
In particular,
we'll arrange both online and
offline study groups where
you'll meet face to face.
We'll support students meetups and
industry events,
and engender a community atmosphere
to ensure your learning experience is
as rich as possible.
We'll also help you interact online
through our forums, Slack and
other online tools.
>> Thank you, Lisbeth.
Here at Udacity we've built a fantastic
support network to help students
like you surpass your expectations.
We hope you take full advantage of these
resources to reach your goals and more.