Hi, I'm Kathleen.
I lead the careers team at UDACITY.
We support students in their job search.
The careers team knows what employers
are looking for in a job candidate.
And we want to work with you to market
yourself as the best person for the job.
Whether it's a new role or
a promotion at your current company.
You need to be proactive in your career
development to be job ready at graduate.
For this reason,
career services are available
throughout your nano degree experience.
It's important to remember, while you're
here to learn the technical skills for
a job, it's equally important to know
how to communicate those skills to
an employer, through an application,
your online profiles, and in interviews.
Let's meet the careers team who
will be with you along the way.
>> Hi, I'm Rachel.
Along with a network of career
mentors our team is here to help
you from when you begin to look for
jobs until you accept your job offer.
Career support is present at different
stages throughout your nano degree and
we encourage you to go through
all of them regardless of where
you are in your job search.
The first of these career
services are the projects in
the Career Development
section of your classroom.
UDACITY career services include guides,
lessons and
personalized feedback on topics
like talking to recruiters,
interviewing and
optimizing your online profiles.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
>> And I'm Trin.
In order to graduate career-ready,
you should continuously work
on your career development.
Like with all learning, beginning
something earlier means you are more
prepared when it's time
to apply that learning.
When your dream job pops up
you want to be ready for it.
We'll support you throughout your
career development, on the forums,
in career coach appointments, and
through the Career Resource Center.
>> Hi, I'm Kirsten and
I head up employer relations at UDACITY.
Once you've completed the curriculum,
you'll be ready to apply to jobs and
talk with employers.
UDACITY partners with industry-leading
companies who are looking to hire
skilled and passionate people, like you.
Having hiring partners means
you'll have direct and
preferential exposure
at these companies.
This will help give you a leg up in your
job search as you explore your career
options, and
develop a career path unique to you.
After you create your first
core nano degree projects,
you'll then be prompted to begin
your career development with us.
>> We'll then be there
with you from then on.
As you explore your career options and
pursue your dream role.
We look forward to working with you.
[MUSIC]