You're probably familiar with the idea of functions.
When to use a function and when not to use one probably comes pretty naturally to you.
One of the best parts about React is that
you can use the same intuition you have about functions,
for when you create React components.
However, instead of your function taking in some arguments or returning a value,
your function is going to take in some arguments and
return some UI. Let's take a look at some code.
Here, we have three functions and one function invocation.
You'll notice our code is clean and organized because
each function has a specific purpose.
We're composing our functions together by having one function get profiled
data whereas the other two functions getProfilePic and getProfileLink.
Now, when we invoke getProfileData,
we get an object back which represents our user.
Now instead of having these functions return an object with data,
let's modify them just a bit to return some UI.
Now don't freak out about the syntax.
We're going to cover this code much more in depth in future lessons.
But for now, notice that instead of composing functions to get some value,
we're composing functions to get some UI.