Before we move on to
the JavaScript language itself,
how about we recap some of
the things you just learned?
First, you learned that all major
browsers come with built-in JavaScript
engines.
This allows browsers to run and
execute JavaScript code.
>> Next, you got practice
using the JavaScript console.
The JavaScript console allows
you to print strings and
execute lines of JavaScript code on
the fly, right inside of your browser.
>> And finally, you wrap up with some
exercises where you use JavaScript
to add styles and
animations to a web page.
>> Hopefully, you're beginning
to see the power of JavaScript.
And you're ready to dive in and
explore the language.
See you in the next lesson.