OK, so now I'm
going to show you
how you actually get these
convolutional codes from the--
this VGG network.
So [INAUDIBLE] where
we're going to take
each of the images
in this flower data
set, and run it through
the convolutional layers,
and get out our code from the
first fully connected layer.
So this is code that's
copied from the source
code of TensorFlow VGG.
So what happens is the
network takes an image that's
244 by 244 by 3,
and then runs it
through this
convolutional layers.
So we can see here we had
like two convolutional layers,
max pooling two [INAUDIBLE]
layers, max pooling.
Then three, and then
three, and then three.
And then finally
after all that, we
get our fully connected layer.
And then that's passed
through ReLU activation.
So it's actually these values
here that we want to get out.
So basically, like this network
was trained using these ReLUs,
and so when we get the
codes, we want to also
use these ReLUs just to--
it'll improve our performance.
So building the network
is pretty straightforward.
So you just create
this VGG object,
and create your input
placeholder, then vgg.build.
So what this does is it
actually like builds a network,
it builds the graph
in TensorFlow,
which you can use later.
And I found like you only
want to build this once.
So like so what happens if you
run vgg.build multiple times,
you just keep adding like all
of these nodes to your graph,
and eventually you
just have too many.
So in this notebook, you want
to be sure to only like run
build just once in
the whole thing.
Otherwise, like
you'll get an error,
and you have to
restart the notebook.
OK, so once we have built
the network, built the graph,
then we just want to
get the codes from--
like I was saying, like
from this layer, ReLU six.
So you just do
session.run, ReLU six,
and feed it your dictionary
with images, and get your codes.
So this part is pretty
simple, but when you actually
like have to go through
the code to do all this,
it actually takes a bit of work
to get everything kind of set
up.
So I'm going to do
most of that, but I'll
have you implement
this part and the code
where we're getting our
convolutional codes out.
OK, so here just
importing the things.
Utils is from TensorFlow VGG.
And this contains some nice
functions like loading images
and that kind of thing.
Then here, just
loading the data.
So basically I've just-- our
data is in flower photos.
And then each of the images is--
like each class-- so there's
like five different classes,
sunflowers, daisies,
roses, et cetera--
So I'm just getting all the--
just listing all the contents
in our data directory
and getting the classes.
So here is what you'll
be doing down here.
So first, you're going
to build the VGG network.
So you're going to
initialize the class
and actually build it.
And then down here
is where you're
going to get the codes
from the ReLU six layer.
So the way this code works is--
I wrote it so that you're
actually running batches
through the network.
So it's looking
through each file,
and it's appending images
to like some batch.
And then we can concatenate the
batch into an array of images,
and then you can
pass the images,
or you can feed the images
into your VGG network
to get ReLU six codes.
This is where we're
loading the image.
So what this actually does--
the images that we have
aren't 244 by 244, which
is what this network
expects, so what this does
is it just crops out the
center part of an image.
So the image is bigger
than 244 by 244,
then it crops out the center
to get that size of image.
So there's other ways to do
this, which are maybe better.
You can scale your original
image down to the size
that it expects, or you
know like some other way
to figure out how to get your
original image, your input
images into the right
shape for the network.
And this is sort
of what you have
to do any time you're
doing transfer learning,
because like all these
convolutional networks were
trained on some
original size of images,
and you have to use
the same size when
you're doing transfer learning.
So I think it's pretty common
to scale your images down.
In this case, I'm just
letting it crop it.
And it worked fine
in this case, but you
might get better results
if you scale your images.
All right, so I will let
you build the network here,
fill in this code, and fill
in this code down here.
Good luck.
And if you get stuck
on this, or if you
want to see how I
did it, like I'll
have a solution video for you.