Hi, there, welcome back.
So this week I'm
going to be talking
about transfer learning.
So in practice most people don't
train their own huge networks
on huge datasets.
So for instance,
if you're training
a convolutional network,
something like AlexNet
on the ImageNet dataset,
it can take multiple weeks
on multiple GPUs.
So it's just not something
that most people have
the time or resources to do.
So instead what you can do
is take a pre-trained network
like AlexNet net
that's been pre-trained
and modify it to use
with your own problem.
So for instance, if
you have some images
that you want to classify
or do some object detection,
you could grab pre-trained
convolutional network
like AlexNet or VGGNet,
and use those instead as
feature extractors
to actually grab
the features from your images.
And then the idea
is that you just
take these last few
fully connected layers.
These are basically just acting
like a classifier, right?
So you just get rid of
those from that network
and you add your own
classifier on top of that.
So there's no book all
be having you implement
some transfer learning to
actually do some image class
classification on a new dataset.
We'll be using the
VGGNet architecture.
I found a GitHub repo
where they've already
pre-trained VGGNet, so we can
just grab that and use it.
So the idea behind
VGGNet is basically this.
I mean you can see
the architecture.
So we have a bunch of
convolutional layers and then
a max-pooling, convolution,
max-pooling, convolution,
max-pooling, and so on.
So we have five of these kind of
convolutional layers going up.
And then at the end we have
three fully connected layers
and then a softmax to
do our classification.
So what we're going to do is
use these convolutional layers
as feature extractors.
Then we're going to toss out
these fully connected layers
and add our own, so that
we can train classifier
for our new images.
So here, this fully
connected layer
after all these
convolutional layers,
it'll be a layer
with 4,096 units
and then we can just use the
activations of all these units
as a code, right?
So it's just kind of
like a convolutional code
that we can use as
input to our classifier.
So our goal here is to
take each of our images
in our new dataset,
pass it through
these convolutional
layers, and get out
this code in this layer.
And this is something you'll
be implementing later on.
So you can read more
about transfer learning
and some other ways to do
this in these course notes
from CS231N.
They're pretty good.
So yeah, just be sure
to check those out
if you want to learn
more about this topic.
So for this
implementation, we're
going to be using code
from this repository.
So TensorFlow VVG.
And this is a VVG network
that has already been trained.
And you can download
the parameters.
So what you'll need to do is
actually clone this repository
before you start.
And in this cell
down here is where
you're going to be
actually downloading
the parameters for this model.
So make sure you do this.
And so download, so
clone the repository
into the same folder where
this notebook is and then
use this to download
the parameters
into that same folder.
And this should all set
it up and do it for you.
And for this one
we're going to be
classifying images of flowers.
So this dataset is actually
from the TensorFlow Inception
Transfer Learning tutorial.
So I'm using a different
network than they are,
but I grabbed the same dataset.
I find that this is typically
a good way to go about it,
because if you know a dataset
works for your problem,
but you have something
different about it,
it's usually good to have, only
change one thing at a time.
So if I know the dataset works,
then and if there's a problem,
then I know it's
something in my network
and not the dataset itself.
Which is why I chose to
use this flower dataset.
So you can read
more about it there.
You can see, you can
read their tutorial
for doing transfer learning
with their interception network.
And here is where we
download the dataset.
So this will just do it for you.