JavaScript is created in just 10
days by Brendan Eich back in 1995,
while Eich was working
on Netscape Navigator.
For those of you don't know,
Netscape Navigator was one of
the Internet's first web browsers.
Today, you use browsers
like Google Chrome,
Mozilla Firefox, Apple Safari, and
Microsoft Edge to surf the web.
>> Prior to Eich's creation of
JavaScript, websites just existed as
pages of HTML and CSS with
the occasional plug-in or Java applet.
>> Wait, Java?
>> Yes, well, at least at first.
JavaScript, what this course is about,
is totally different and
not related to Java in any way.
The fact is, JavaScript has had sort
of a weird past when it comes to names.
JavaScript was originally
called LiveScript but
it was changed back to JavaScript
as a marketing decision in
order to piggyback off
the popularity of Java at the time.
As the language evolved, competing
versions of the language emerged.
So JavaScript was eventually
taken to Ecma International so
that an official standard for
the language could be formed.
>> Today, the language itself is
still referred to as JavaScript.
But recent versions are referenced
by their ECMAScript version number,
like ES5 or ES6.
Even more recently, the standards body
has transitioned to a year-based number
to promote a more
consistent release cycle.
So we have now have ES2016,
ES2017, and so on.
I know, it's confusing.
>> All things considered, JavaScript
has grown to be one of the most popular
languages in the world and is considered
one of the three foundational pillars of
front end web development.