in this video i am going to show you how
to get to Google Chrome's developers
tool to access JavaScript console.
You're going to be using the console to
run most of the code that you write in
this course.
if you are already using Google Chrome
then what you see in this video should
match up in what you
see on your computer.
But if you're not using Google Chrome,
then skip ahead to the next section for
instructions on how to access
developer tools in other browsers, and
then come back to this video.
All right,
now the first thing you'll need to
do is to open up developer tools.
You can do this by right clicking
on the page, and selecting Inspect.
Once you have developer tools open,
you can find the JavaScript Console
by clicking on the Console tab.
If you like keyboard shortcuts,
you can also use Cmd+Option+J on a Mac
to open the console, or
you can use Ctrl+Shift+J on Windows.
There's a really useful reference
of keyboard shortcuts for
developer tools linked below this video.
All right, so now that you have
the JavaScript console open,
let's write your first
line of JavaScript code.
One thing you could do
is write your name.
But just writing your name will actually
result in an error as you can see here.
To be able to actually write your
name in JavaScript without any error
you need to format your name
as a data type called a string
by putting it inside quotes.
Why don't we try something else?
Here's some code that creates
an alert window that says, Hello,
Julia, how are you?
And it pushes it to the browser.
There you go.
Now writing code directly in your
browser is something you can do to test
out new code snippets where you're
not really sure what they do.
But it could actually get pretty
annoying once you starting writing
larger and larger programs.
For example, if you wanted to create
two alerts instead of just one,
it may seem simple at first, but each
time you need to go to the next line,
you would have to type Shift+Return
instead of just the Return key.
This is going to get pretty
annoying pretty fast.
Eventually in the next course,
you'll learn about other ways
to run JavaScript files.
But for now we recommend using a text
editor like Atom or Sublime Text and
then pasting your code in the console
once you're ready to test it.