Hi I'm Shanon Bradshaw director of education
at MongoDB, MongoDB is the company behind the
open source noSQL database of the same name. Prior to joining MongoDB, I was a
computer scientist working in academia and consulting
on a number of different data science projects
in the financial industry, social media and other
spaces. This is a class about data wrangling.
Data scientist spend about 70% of their time data
wrangling. So what is data wrangling? Well, it's a process
of gathering, extracting, cleaning, and storing our data. Only
after that does it really make sense to do any
analysis. So if you're quantum wall street and you
want to build models to automate trading you first need
to make sure you're basing your models on reliable
data. Or if you're building a map app you need
to ensure your data's correct, or you can quickly find yourself in something
of a public relations disaster. As another example if you're working on
a smaller scale Analyzing data for a research team, you want to
ensure your team can make decisions based on the data you're providing. If
you don't take the time to ensure your data is in good
shape before doing any analysis, you run a big risk of wasting
a lot of time later on, or worse, losing the faith of
your colleagues, who depend on the data you've prepared. It's a little like
putting the cart before the horse. So while we're going
to get to some analysis, That's why we're doing all this
in the first place. This class is really about getting
your data ready so that any analysis is built on a
solid foundation of good data. Here you're going to get
a chance to do some tinkering. We're going to develop your
hacker muscles, or, should I say, wrangler muscles. We'll work
with lots of different types of data. For music, energy, Wikipedia,
and Twitter, to name a few. We'll also teach you how
to work with data in most of the formats you're likely
to see. JSON, XML, CSV, Excel, and HTML. And even some
legacy text formats. In the last half of the course, we'll
show you how to store your data in MondoDB, and use
it to support analysis. Mongo DB is becoming increasingly important to
data scientists around the world, as a powerful and scalable tool
for big data problems. And we'll wrap it up with a
case study, that allows you to put all the pieces together.
We're happy to have you in the class. Let's get started.