Hi, welcome to the program.
We're thrilled to have you here, and I'm
looking forward to guiding your journey
to the cutting edge of
artificial intelligence.
You are now an essential member
of the Udacity community.
We're here to make sure you
fulfill your goals, but
we also want to learn from you.
Your experience will guide future
development, and we'd love to hear your
thoughts on how we can improve and
make this program better for others.
Now let's take a quick walk through
the Udacity office to get a flavor of
how we do things here.
So we believe in learning by doing.
So rather than simply watching videos,
or
taking tests on AI, you'll build
real artificial intelligence.
And watch those AIs solve complex
problems that humans like me and
you simply can't do with
the same speed or accuracy.
>> Hey, can I get some help?
>> Yeah, of course.
Looks like we can just sub
in 0.9 here from here.
And looks like we can
likewise sub in 0.8 here.
You want to finish the rest?
Looks like we got it.
[MUSIC]
In the first project, you build a simple
AI agent that solves any Sudoku problem
in the world, and
learn two foundational AI techniques.
Constraint propagation, and search.
This project is just a little teaser
to get your feet wet, and show you how
quickly you can start applying AI
concepts to problems around you.
Hey Christina.
>> Hey, Dhruv.
>> Nice work, solving Sudoku.
You'll also be given the chance to go
above and beyond by using advanced Sudoku
strategies to improve
the speed of your agent.
[MUSIC]
In the next project,
you'll build an AI agent that can
routinely defeat opponents in Isolation.
Here you'll apply Minimax and
Alpha-beta pruning,
two strategies used by Google's
world-beating Go agent AlphaGo.
You go on to create an AI that
guides Pac-Man through his maze and
allows him to eat all the food in
the most efficient way possible.
Definitely more efficient
than Ryan over here.
>> I'm still practicing.
>> Using simple techniques
such as breadth-first search,
depth-first search and A-Star search
your AI agent will traverse Pac-Man's
maze faster than any other human player.
Next you will be tasked with
finding the optimal route for
taking cargo from one place to another.
Planning problems like this are the very
core of the logistics industry.
And you'll see just how powerful AI is
in solving these kinds of problems.
And finally, you use hidden Markov
models to automatically read sign
languages characters and convert them
into their English text counterparts.
This is just one of
the many examples of how AI
is making a meaningful
impact in society at large.
And all this is just in term one.
We think you'll have a lot of fun, and
we can't wait to see you get started.