Hi, I'm Sebastian,
I'm delighted to welcome you to
Udacity's Artificial Intelligence
Nano Degree program.
We think it provides
an experience unlike any other.
AI is really about unleashing one of
the most amazing things in the entire
universe, intelligence.
AI is growing exponentially.
And we've changed our world at the rate
with the fast to fast work by humans,
because AIs can learn
much faster than us.
Just look at self-driving cars.
Anytime you drive,
only one person gets better.
You.
But with AI, anytime an AI car drives,
all cars get better,
including all future unborn cars.
After completing this program, you'll
be positioned to take full advantage
of such changes that AI will usher in.
You will be ready to work with
trans-disciplinary thinkers and
practitioners to create technologies
that will shape our future world.