Hi, I'm Julia.
>> And, I'm James.
>> We'll be your instructors for
this introductory course on JavaScript.
JavaScript is a programming
language created for the web.
If you're familiar with using HTML and
CSS to create webpages, JavaScript is
the final piece that you'll need to
really make your websites come to life.
>> Back in 1995, when Brandan Eich
created a JavaScript, it was created to
make it easier to add interactive and
dynamic elements to websites.
But today, JavaScript is used for
all sorts of applications.
>> From programming a robot with
Arduino to writing a game
script in Unity.
In fact, even some code editors
were built with JavaScript.
The point is, the opportunities
with JavaScript are endless.
>> In this course,
you'll learn about the foundations of
the JavaScript programming language.
And along the way,
you'll familiarize yourself with the
tools used by JavaScript programmers.
Finally, we want to make sure you get
enough practice with the basics of
the language.
So between each section, you'll have
access to the problem sets that
reinforce the topics we just learned.
>> Before we get started,
let's take a quick detour to talk
a little bit about JavaScript's history.