A programming language is used for
a computer to understand.
But as your code gets more and more
complex, it can get harder and harder
for you and other humans to read your
code and to understand what it does.
Comments are often used by developers to
help clarify the meaning of your code
in a human-friendly language.
In JavaScript, a comment is any
text after a double forward slash
if you want to write comments
one line at a time like this, or
any text in between a slash star and
star slash if you know you're going
to be writing a block of comments.
Comments are not executed by
the JavaScript interpreter, so
you could pretty much say
anything you want in the comment.
But usually you try to make them
a little more useful than this.
For example, here's some code
I wrote a while ago, and
it's not really obvious to me
what I was doing with this code.
There's seems to be a function,
a for loop,
some variables with really
bad variable names.
Don't worry if you don't know
what any of these means just yet.
What you need to know right now is
that if I had used comments like this,
I would, and you probably would too,
have an easier time remembering
what this code was originally for.
See, now I can tell that this function
reverses the order of characters in
a word, and it does this by looping
over the characters in reverse order and
adding them to a new word.
Some of the quizzes in this course might
include comments that give you hints or
instructions to complete a quiz.
We encourage you to use
comments in your own code
to explain any non-obvious code
you write in your quizzes.
Not only will you develop
good coding habits, but
you will also improve
the readability of your code
if you ever need to refer back
to these quizzes for review.
All right, now it's time to
go on to your first quiz.
Good luck.