Let's take a look at
the string datatype.
You've actually used a string before,
and maybe just didn't know it.
When you type a message
inside console.log,
that message is actually
just a JavaScript string.
So here, Hiya, Friend, is just a string.
Strings can be single letters,
like the character h, or
even contain numbers,
like the string 123.
The important thing is that you
use quotes to signify a string.
It doesn't matter if
the quotes are single or
double quotes, but
they do have to match.
I used double quotes here and
single quotes here.
If I try to pass the string
to console.log but
forget to use the quotes,
JavaScript will return back an error.
I get this reference error, because
the JavaScript engine thinks I'm talking
about a variable called hello instead
of a string with the value of hello.
We haven't talked about variables just
yet, but the moral of the story here
is to remember to use
quotes when using strings.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
If I add the quotes in, then the string
gets printed out to the console.
[BLANK_AUDIO]