Data is everywhere.
It's the grade you made
on your first math test,
it's the conversation you
have with a loved one and
it's the decision you made to
sit down and watch this video.
All of these things can
be represented as data.
Data's important because it helps us
understand the world, recognize trends,
make educated guesses and
inform our future decisions.
>> This is no different in programming.
Data and data types are the building
blocks of any programming language
because they help us
organize information and
determine how our programs will run.
>> When you look on your Facebook
profile, what do you see?
Your name, the number of friends you
have, the date of your last post,
list of status updates and whether you
liked the comment your friend just made.
All this information is being gathered,
calculated and
presented to your friends and
family visiting your profile.
>> And when you look at your
bank account, what do you see?
An account number, an account balance,
dates of each transaction and
the name of the company that
you made a purchase from.
It's important to be aware of what
types of data you're using and
when it's appropriate to use each type.
>> In this lesson, we'll start
by learning how to define and
manipulate the primitive
data types of JavaScript.
Numbers, strings, Booleans,
undefined and null.
Once you're familiar with these data
types, you'll see how you can store data
into variables so you can reuse and
manipulate data throughout your code.