My name is Sebastian.
I welcome you to our
self driving car nanodegree
The self driving car
started when I was 18.
One of my best friends in the
neighborhood died in a traffic accident.
His life went away in no time.
And back in the day, I asked myself,
why is it that we have these machines
that are great on one hand,
but still kill so many people?
It stuck with me for a long time.
And when I joined Stanford in 2003,
the US government
had just launched a competition
called the DARPA Grand Challenge.
It's a competition where a self driven
car had to drive through an empty desert
in California.
Our car Stanley,
named after Stanford was a blue,
beautiful Volkswagen Touareg.
And lo and
behold we won the competition.
My team joined Google in 2009 to build
a self driving car that could drive
on public streets where we all drive.
And when we were ready to
tell the public about it,
we had driven not just 100,000 unique
miles for the self driving cars.
But we've also driven pretty much
the hardest streets in California you
can imagine, completely self driven.
We drove from San Francisco
to Los Angeles.
The technology has been in
development for many, many decades,
but the breakthroughs
are often most recent years.
More than self driven cars
now we have proven others can
drive safer than humans can drive and
automotive companies and
tech companies are struggling to
find great engineers to keep up.
This is the self driven program and
when you are finished,
you will have the skills to drawing
this cutting edge industry.
We are super excited
to have you with us.