So far, we've looked at the data
types number, string, and boolean.
But there are couple more we need
to look at, and those are null and
undefined.
At first,
they might seem somewhat confusing,
because they are pretty similar.
So you might want to replay this
explanation a couple of times.
Null is a data type that has no value,
just like how you can set
a variable to a value of 10.
You could explicitly set
a variable to a value of null.
Undefined is a data type that
indicates the absence of value.
It's a bit confusing, but
it's not the same as null.
Null is a value that means nothing or
totally empty.
But undefined actually means
does not have a value,
not even a value of nothing.
You could declare a variable x and try
to use it, and it will return undefined.
It's undefined because
the variable x exists,
it just doesn't have a value yet.
If you set a variable to
the value of null and
try to use it, it will return null.
In other words,
undefined will be returned to you, if
you didn't assign a value to something.
Null will be returned
if you purposefully
assigned the value to nothing.