You've now seen how you can
perform basic operations,
as well as comparisons on numbers and
strings.
>> Whenever you compare data,
the result of the comparison will
always be a value of true or false.
This is important because our
third primitive data type,
Booleans, only includes
these two values.
>> Just think, yes or no, on and
off, true or false, ones and zeroes.
These are all values that really
represent the same thing.
>> And this Boolean logic is a huge
part of how we think about problems.
Code either runs or
it doesn't, there's no in-between,
at least not in programming.
>> In this section, you'll dive deeper
into Booleans by comparing data of
different types and learning about
different ways to express equality.