Welcome to the program,
I'm Richard the curriculum lead for Front-end Web Development at Udacity.
You're now an essential member of
the Udacity community and we are so excited to have you here.
I'm looking forward to helping guide your journey through React.
And in this program you'll be building applications along with Michael, Ryan and Tyler.
These projects are ones that you'll be building in class while learning React.
Here at your Udacity we can't stress enough the importance of learning by doing.
So in addition to the in-class projects,
you'll also be given some projects that you'll build on your own.
These projects will prove how much you've learned. It'll be great.
For the first project you'll build an application called My Reads.
This app will require you to manage state,
build components and leverage React Router.
This project is all about mastering the fundamentals of React.
Now by fundamentals I mean the stuff you'll be doing
in every single React project you create.
Check out the following sections for a more in-depth look at what you'll be building.